Activity 2:

1. Explain in your own words the relationship between a deck and a card.
	A deck has one or more cards.  This is an aggregation because the card can exist
	independently but the deck cannot.

2. Consider the deck initialized with the statements below. How many cards does the deck contain?
String[] ranks = {"jack", "queen", "king"};
String[] suits = {"blue", "red"};
int[] pointValues = {11, 12, 13};
Deck d = new Deck(ranks, suits, pointValues);
	6

3. The game of Twenty-One is played with a deck of 52 cards. Ranks run from ace (highest) 
down to 2 (lowest). Suits are spades, hearts, diamonds, and clubs as in many other games.
A face card has point value 10; an ace has point value 11; point values for 2, …, 10 are 
2, …, 10, respectively. Specify the contents of the ranks, suits, and pointValues arrays 
so that the statement
Deck d = new Deck(ranks, suits, pointValues);
initializes a deck for a Twenty-One game.
	String[] ranks = {"Two", "Three", "Four", "Five", "Six", "Seven", "Eight", "Nine", "Ten",
				"Jack", "Queen", "King", "Ace"};
	String[] suits = {"Spades", "Heats", "Diamonds", "Clubs"};
	int[] pointvalues = {2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 10, 10, 10, 11};
	Deck d = new Deck(ranks, suits, pointValues);

4. Does the order of elements of the ranks, suits, and pointValues arrays matter?
	The order of the ranks and pointValues matter, suits does not.  For example the if "Three"
	is the second index in ranks, 3 needs to be the second value in pointValues.


Actvity 3:

1.  Write a static method named flip that simulates a flip of a weighted coin by returning either
"heads" or "tails" each time it is called. The coin is twice as likely to turn up heads as tails.
Thus, flip should return "heads" about twice as often as it returns "tails."
	public static String flip(String[] args)
	{
		int result = (int) (Math.random * 3);
		if (result == 0)
		{
			return "tails";
		}
		return "heads";
	}

2. Write a static method named arePermutations that, given two int arrays of the same length
but with no duplicate elements, returns true if one array is a permutation of the other (i.e., the
arrays differ only in how their contents are arranged). Otherwise, it should return false.
	public static boolean arePermutaions(int[] first, int[] second)
	{
		for (int i = 0; i < first.length; i++)
		{
			int count = 0;
			for (int j = 0; j < second.length; i++)
			{
				if (first[i] == second[j])
				{
					count++;
				}
			}
			if (count != 1)
			{
				return false;
			}
		}
		return true;
	}

3. Suppose that the initial contents of the values array in Shuffler.java are {1, 2, 3, 4}.
For what sequence of random integers would the efficient selection shuffle change values to
contain {4, 3, 2, 1}?
	0, 1, 0.


Activity 5

Buggy1:
isEmpty returned false instead of true:
return size == 1; instead of size == 0;:

Buggy2:
size method returns 0 when it should be 1:
The method could always return 0.  return 0; instead of return size;:

Buggy3:
shuffle does not shuffle the deck:
Math.random() is never used to find a random index to be repaced with. Every card replaces itself.:

Buggy4:
deal returns null instead of a card:
it may return the card at index 1 instead of 0:


Activity 6

1. List all possible plays for the board 5♠ 4♥ 2♦ 6♣ A♠ J♥ K♦ 5♣ 2♠
	5♠ and 6♣, 6♣ and 5♣.

2. If the deck is empty and the board has three cards left, must they be J, Q, and K? Why
or why not?
	Yes because for it to be any other combination the last pair/triple would only be
	two cards, not three.

3. Does the game involve any strategy? That is, when more than one play is possible, does 
it matter which one is chosen? Briefly explain your answer.
	No because regardless of else happens, you will be able to make all of the current
	possilbe moves and be able to draw the next cards anyways.


Activity 7

1. What items would be necessary if you were playing a game of Elevens at your desk (not on the
computer)? List the private instance variables needed for the ElevensBoard class.
	A deck of cards and a surface (the desk).
	Instance variables: Deck , board, cards on the board.

2. Write an algorithm that describes the actions necessary to play the Elevens game.
	Deal the top 9 cards in the deck. Once the users select a possible match (add up to 11 or 
	jack-queen-king) and hit the replace button, put the selected cards into a discard pile 
	and deal new cards to replace the selected ones. When there are no more cards left on the 
	board or if there are no more legal moves, the game ends.

3. Now examine the partially implemented ElevensBoard.java file found in the Activity7
Starter Code directory. Does the ElevensBoard class contain all the state and behavior
necessary to play the game?
	Yes, it does.


4. ElevensBoard.java contains three helper methods. These helper methods are private
because they are only called from the ElevensBoard class.
a. Where is the dealMyCards method called in ElevensBoard?
	At the start of a new game or creation or an ElevensBoardObject.

b. Which public methods should call the containsPairSum11 and containsJQK
methods?
	anotherPlayIsPossible and isLegal

c. It’s important to understand how the cardIndexes method works, and how the list that it
returns is used. Suppose that cards contains the elements shown below. Trace the execution
of the cardIndexes method to determine what list will be returned. Complete the diagram
below by filling in the elements of the returned list, and by showing how those values index
cards. Note that the returned list may have less than 9 elements.

cards ->        0  1  2    3  4    5    6  7  8
	        J♥ 6♣ null 2♠ null null A♠ 4♥ null

returned ->     0  1 2  3  4 
list       	0  1 3  6  7



d. Complete the following printCards method to print all of the elements of cards that are
indexed by cIndexes.

public static printCards(ElevensBoard board)
{
	List<Integer> cIndexes = board.cardIndexes();
	/* Your code goes here. */

	for (Integer i : cIndexes)
	{
		int a = (int) (i);
		System.out.println(cards[a]);
	}

}


e. Which one of the methods that you identified in question 4b above needs to call the
cardIndexes method before calling the containsPairSum11 and containsJQK
methods? Why?
	isLegal. To insure that the cards selected are the same as the ones that 
	can be selected.

	


